♪ In the not too distant
future, next Sunday AD ♪
♪ There was a guy named Joel ♪
♪ Not too different
from you or me ♪
♪ He worked at
Gizmonic Institute ♪
♪ Just another face
in a red jumpsuit ♪
♪ He did a good job
cleaning up the place ♪
♪ But his bosses
didn't like him ♪
♪ So they shot him into space ♪
♪ We'll send him cheesy movies ♪
♪ The worst we can find ♪
♪ La, la, la ♪
♪ He'll have to sit
and watch them all ♪
♪ Then we'll monitor his mind ♪
♪ La, la, la ♪
♪ Now keep in mind
Joel can't control ♪
♪ Where the movies
begin or end ♪
♪ La, la, la ♪
♪ Because he used
those special parts ♪
♪ To make his robot friends ♪
♪ Robot roll call ♪
♪ Cambot ♪
♪ Pan left ♪
♪ Gypsy ♪
♪ Hi, girl ♪
♪ Tom Servo ♪
♪ What a cool guy ♪
♪ Crow ♪
♪ What a wisecracker ♪
♪ If you're wondering how
he eats and breathes ♪
♪ And other science facts ♪
♪ La, la, la ♪
♪ Then repeat to yourself
it's just a show ♪
♪ I should really just relax ♪
♪ For "Mystery Science
Theater 3000" ♪
- Yeah, it's Harry
Connick's girlfriend.
- Oh yeah.
- Oh look over here,
more Christmas catalogs.
L.L. Bean, Neiman Marcus,
Monkey Wards, Fisher Nuts,
Edmund Scientific, oh,
Uncle Bob's Produce Ranch.
- For the traditional
yuletide cabbage.
- Right you are.
And for the elite little ones,
The Magical World
of FAO Schwartz.
- Parents, remember,
kids always know best,
so get 'em whatever they want.
Look, a $900 taffeta
octopus outfit, thanks Dad.
- Oh, and look over here,
a golf ball polisher,
only 400 bucks at
The Sharper Image.
Glad tidings, glad tidings.
You know, Crow, when I see
these catalogs in their
enchanting, suitable-for-framing
covers, I'm reminded
of the true joy of a
New England Christmas.
A gentle snow, all of us
snuggled into a blanket
as we race home to our
cozy hearth and warm fire
in our furry little surrey.
- Hey, in fact, there it is.
- What?
- Only $5,900
from Neiman Marcus, a
furry little surrey.
- Oh, let me see, wow.
- You know, Tommy, when
I see these catalogs,
all I can see are 800,000 acres
of decimated old-growth forests.
- Oh, Crow, is that really
the Christmas spirit?
- [Computer] Commercial
sign in 15 seconds.
- Hey you guys,
what are you doin'?
- Just lookin' at
catalogs, dreamin'.
- Have you guys thought about
what you want for Christmas?
- Yeah, me, me, I
want a Ted Williams
signature inflatable
bathtub pillow.
- I want a pony.
- Oh, Gypsy, we don't
have room on this ship
- Please, please
- For a pony.
No, can't do it.
What about you, Crow?
- I wanna decide who
lives and who dies.
- Oh, I don't know.
- [Computer] Commercial sign
in five, four, three, two,
commercial sign now.
- We'll be right back.
- You're next.
- Beet nose.
- Hey.
(mellow music)
- Earth to Joel,
New Center calling.
- Hey, what does that make me?
- Sleep in heavenly peace.
Frank, it's time to reveal
this week's invention exchange.
- And boy is it
ever gonna sting.
- Sting is right.
The holiday season is here.
The boss is on vacation,
and we've gone crazy.
Now I know from experience
that nothing chafes
a kid's hinder more
than his request
for a neat toy maligned into
a safe and practical gift.
Enter the wish-squisher.
- Yeah, what ya do is ya take
a really cool toy that
any kid would dig,
like these video
cassette cartridge games.
You take it, stick it
through the wish-squisher.
Voila.
- And it comes out
as annoying and practical
as any gift from Aunt Vida.
Check it out, Underoos that
won't fit for two years.
- And what kid
wouldn't love as a gift
more money than he or
she will ever deserve,
but then suddenly, it
starts to get weird.
The rules change.
You start to feel kind of bad.
- Yes, what was once the
bright promise for the future,
becomes your four-year-old
sister's raisin collection.
- And nothing, and I mean
nothing, is more fun than
racing slot cars
just like this one,
around the Christmas tree.
But no.
- What was once
your first draft,
grade A choice from your
parents as a gift becomes socks.
- Socks, ladies and gentlemen.
Yes, what was once
crummy speedball black
and green rayon encrusted
uncomfortable socks, becomes--
- Run it through again, Frank.
- Okay, running it
through the wish-squisher.
It becomes--
- A gift certificate
for a stationery store.
Joel.
- You know, Joel,
I was wondering,
do you think if they sent
that really crummy gift
through the machine again,
it might turn into
something neat?
- Hush, boy, you'll
anger the overlords.
Hello, sirs.
Our invention exchange
this week is based on
our yuletide musings
about what would be on the
Island of Misfit Toys,
based on Rankin Bass's
production of "Rudolph
the Red-Nose Reindeer."
- Whoever heard of a
Charlie in the box?
- Exactly, check it out.
Here's a new contribution,
buttery, sweet toaster dolls.
- Ohhh.
- Yeah.
- Yeah, or play Patrick
Swayze's Road House board game.
(Tom humming upbeat jazz)
Become a highly paid
Tai Chi wielding,
philosophically
alert bouncer like
Patrick Swayze in "Road House."
Shake the dice.
Get in a potentially
dangerous situation
and use the catch phrase cards
to lash out at your
opponents with sayings like,
"It's my way or the highway,"
"Hurts, don't it?"
And, "You're my new
Saturday night thing."
- Yeah.
- Wooo.
- Or, you can have
absolutely no fun whatsoever
with this easy-bake foundry.
The light bulb-powered
blast furnace
turns inexpensive pig iron
you find around the house
into high grade steel
that's ready for market!
- Okay, and what do
you have for us, Gypsy?
(mumbling)
What?
Oh come on, open your mouth.
(retching)
- Oh!
- Bleck!
- Oh, oh, oh my god!
- A hairball!
- Aw, no it's not.
It's Gypsy's contribution to
the New Island of Misfit Toys,
Mr. Mashed Potato Head.
- Oh, puke, ugh.
- What do you think, sirs?
- Ours was better.
- And now a Deep 13
holiday presentation,
Pia Zadora in "Santa Claus
Conquers the Martians."
Shield your eyes, Frank.
- Thank you.
(alarm buzzing)
- Oh, we got movie sign!
(screaming)
♪ Hooray for Santa Claus ♪
♪ Hooray for, jumping jiminy ♪
- [Joel] By order of
the Fire Marshall,
there's no smoking
in this theater.
- [Tom] And kids, don't
miss Santa at Apache Plaza.
- Hey, hold on, isn't there a,
uh, title to this movie?
- [Tom] I think it's either
"Santa Claus Conquers
"the Martians" or "Road
House," I'm not sure.
- Oh, "Road House," woo!
- [Tom] I bet Patrick
Swayze beats the crap
outta all these people
during the movie.
(laughing)
- [Joel] Big John
Call is Santa Claus
in "Oh Little Town
of Deathlehem."
- Oh man, this is really,
really cheap animation.
"Clutch Cargo" was
better than this.
- Adapted from the
novel by Eudora Wilton.
- Custume designer?
Custume?
- C-U-S.
(laughing)
♪ Hooray for Santy Claus ♪
- [Tom] Hey, it's delightful,
it's delicious, it's Delugg.
(all shouting)
Oh, it's okay.
- [Joel] It seems
like Santa's sultry.
That's a very lovely dress
you're wearing, ho ho ho.
We got the Ohio
Players coming up next.
- [Tom] Yeah, I'd say
there was a little nepotism
in the Wright family there, huh?
(laughing)
Like father like son.
- Ah, Martian furniture
by Fritz of Mars.
- [Tom] Toys by Marx.
Oh look, and Reverend
Schuller at the Crystal Tower
Cathedral fountain thing.
- [Joel] Oh, brown, great,
they're running out of colors.
♪ Hooray for Santy Claus ♪
- [Tom] Well, that was nice.
- This is the kookiest credits
sequence since "Mannequin."
[Tom] Okay, thank
you for the song!
♪ Hooray for Santy Claus ♪
♪ Cha cha cha ♪
- [Tom] Ooh, good timing.
- At this time, station
KID-TV brings you
the special event of the year.
- Big Brother is watching, kids!
- Kid Brother is watching you.
- At this very moment,
KID-TV has standing
by a television crew
at Santa Claus' workshop.
- [Tom] Uh, straighten, please.
Straighten?
- Correspondent Andy
Henderson will bring you
a person to person interview
with Santa Claus himself
direct from the North Pole.
- [Joel] Oh, he's
just being obtuse.
(laughing)
- At the moment, the temperature
is 91 degrees below zero.
(eerie music)
- [Tom] Kids, you
probably shouldn't sit
so close to the TV.
- [Joel] And don't slouch.
- [Announcer] Andy
Henderson at the North Pole.
- Hi, kids!
This is Andy Henderson
at the North Pole.
- Uh, no you're not,
you're Rip Taylor.
- It's cold up here! (laughing)
From this spot, there's only
one direction you can go.
- To hell.
- And that's south.
Living up here is pretty rough.
I don't see how Santa stands it.
- [Joel] Hey, fur kills, Andy.
- Here we eat nothing
but frozen food.
At least, that's the way it
is by the time we get it.
- [Tom] You know, elf
tastes just like chicken.
- And now, let's take a
look-see into Santa's workshop.
- [Joel] Ah, we'll
wait here, then.
- [Tom] Yeah, please, thank you.
(quirky music)
- Whoa, whoa, it smells
like a monkey house in here.
- Hello again.
- [Tom] Got a long
mic cord there.
- Boys and girls, it's just
weeks before Christmas,
and Santa and his helpers
are working overtime
to make sure that
there's enough toys
for the kids all over the world.
- [Joel] All over the world!
- Santa's a pretty
busy man, but I'm sure
he'd like to say a
few words to you kids.
- [Tom] Oh, I dunno.
- Hello, Santa.
- Get the hell out of my shop!
- Oh, oh, hello, boys and girls!
- Smoking is good
for you, ho ho ho!
- Andy, you caught me
at a very busy time.
- Well, you think you'll
be ready by Christmas Eve?
- Well, we've never
disappointed the kids yet.
- [Joel] Except
for the poor ones.
- Tell me, is it
true that this year,
there's a rumor that you're
going to use a rocket sled?
- No sirree, we're going out
the good old-fashioned way.
- [Joel] Guns a-blazing.
- Prancer and Dancer
and Donder and Blitzen
and Vixen and Nixon.
- [Tom] Yes, and what's
in the pipe, sir?
- Oh, I always, consarn it,
I get those names mixed up,
but the kids know their names.
- Yeah, 'cause they're sober.
- Santa, there you are.
- [Joel] It's Barbara Bush!
- We have so much to do,
and you stand here dawdling,
talking to this visitor.
- Mr. Anderson,
this is Mrs. Claus.
- [Tom] Hands off.
- Dear, we're on television.
- How do you do, Mr. Anderson?
- Ma'am.
- Now, I want you
to go and finish
painting those hobby horses!
Television?
Did you say we're on television?
♪ Ed Sullivan ♪
- Why didn't you tell me?
My hair's a mess!
- [Joel] Hi, Mom.
- [Tom] When she thinks
of the mass media,
she touches herself.
(laughing)
- (laughing) We're
having her committed.
- Come along, Mr. Anderson.
And I'll show you some of the
new toys we're turning out.
- Oh, looks like C.
Everett Koop's children
are employed here.
- [Tom] Union meeting
tonight, pass it on.
- Everything is a-okay, Santa.
- Good man.
- [Joel] Blinky, sir.
- Winky is in charge
of our special parts.
- [Joel] Blinky.
- Oh, uh, now here, here
is the latest toy rocket.
It runs on real rocket fuel.
- Really?
I've been wondering,
what is this
strange little
creature over there?
- I'm Batman.
- Oh, Winky made that.
- [Joel] Blinky, sir.
- That's his idea of a Martian.
- A Martian?
Wowwee wow, I'd hate to
meet a creature like that
on a dark night.
- [Tom] I'd hate to meet
Blinky on a dark night.
- I wonder if there
really are people on Mars.
- Well, who knows.
- Makes ya think,
don't it, huh?
- Well, if there are, I hope
they have someone like you
up there, Santa, to
bring joy and good cheer
to all the Martian children.
- [Tom] Ho ho ho,
you flatter me.
- Keep going, Winky,
Christmas Eve is coming soon.
Now, Mr. Anderson, I
wanna show you some--
(whooshing)
(imitating whooshing)
- [Tom] Meanwhile, at
Oscar Wilde's house.
- Dropo, you lazy
good-for-nothing, where are you!
- [Crow] Tonight
I'm a space pirate.
Permission to come aboard!
- [Tom] Woohoo.
- Dropo.
Dropo, wake up!
Wake up!
(chuckling)
- [Joel] Ah, ah, ah,
get the spiders off!
Off, off me!
- Turn off that tickle ray!
- [Tom] Before I can't fake
laugh any more! (laughing)
- Stand up.
- [Tom] Hey.
- [Kimar] Stand up!
Stand up!
- [Tom] And be counted!
- I'm sorry, Chief Kimar, sir.
- Dropo, you are the
laziest man on Mars.
Why are you sleeping
during the working hours?
- [Tom] 'Cause I'm the
laziest man on Mars.
- I wasn't sleeping, Chief.
It's just that I haven't
been able to sleep
these last few nights.
- He's been drunk
off his Martian butt.
- So I was just practicing.
(laughing)
- [Tom] (chuckling) Kill him.
- Well, I suggest you
practice doing your work.
Where's Lady Momar?
- [Joel] Qaddafi?
- She went to the
food pill center
to get some new food pills.
- See, 'cause it's Mars.
Yeah.
- It's no wonder.
They sit in front of
the video set all day
watching those ridiculous
Earth programs.
It confuses them.
- [Tom] Especially "Twin Peaks."
- Where are they?
- Oh, in there,
watching Earth programs.
- [Joel] Uh, it's Sweeps Week.
- [Tom] Open, Coco
the Clown room!
- [Andy] Say, Santa,
what have we here?
- [Joel] You know, Pia
Zadora never got much taller
than she is in this.
- [Santa] Walks, talks,
cries, and she even sings.
- But she wants to direct.
- [Andy] Almost like a
real live little girl.
- [Santa] That she
is, sir, that she is.
All she needs is
tender loving care.
- [Tom] And 20 bucks worth
of batteries.
- Bromar, what is a doll?
- I don't know, Girmar.
What is tender loving care?
- I don't know either.
- Bomar, Girmar.
I've told you not to watch
those silly Earth programs.
- Like "Firing Line."
- Now, go to sleep.
- Must we go to
sleep now, Father?
I want to see Santa
Claus some more.
- I want to see more toys.
- No, go to sleep.
- Will you buy me a
Golden Globe, then?
- [Tom] Why, sure.
Well, she'll serve 12, and with
a little Martian seasoning,
she'll make a
tempting main course.
(smacking lips)
(mellow music)
- We need your advice, Chochem.
- [Joel] Buy Polaroid?
- Something is wrong
with our children.
- [Tom] On Saturn 3.
- They eat not, they sleep not.
- They are not.
- Their only interest
is watching meaningless
Earth programs on the video.
- [Joel] Are there
any other kind?
But I digress.
- What time of year is it now?
- [Kimar] It is the
middle of Septober.
- [Tom] Oh, time
for Septoberfest.
- No, no.
Not here.
I mean on Earth.
- [Joel] Guy looks
like a troll doll.
- [Tom] He does.
- Ah yes.
- I had Jell-o today.
- It is early December on Earth.
Close to the time
of the Christmas.
- [Tom] Uh, hello,
Mars to Chochem.
- That explains it.
- What is a Christmas?
- [Joel] It's a Christian
holiday ruined by commercialism.
- Of great joy and peace
on the planet Earth.
- [Tom] Look, we caught you at
a bad time, we'll come back.
- And to children, it is
also a time of anticipation.
- Hey, uh, just in case,
where are your nitro pills?
- As they await the
arrival of Santa Claus.
- [Joel] He's Howard Hughes!
- [Tom] Oh!
- And his gifts.
- Bah!
(all bleating)
Nonsense.
- What has this to do with
our children, ancient one?
- We have no children on Mars.
- I have no son.
- They have children's
bodies, but with adult minds.
- [Tom] Oh, like Drew Barrymore.
- They do not have a childhood.
I've seen this
coming for centuries.
- Why didn't you tell us, Pops?
- They are born, our
electronic teaching machines
are attached to their brains
(yawning)
while they are in their cradles.
Information is fed into their
minds in a constant stream.
(whistling)
- Look, you're breaking
my heart, Gramps.
Can you get on with it?
- They are adults.
- [Tom] And they go
through shoes like crazy.
- They never played.
They never learned to have fun.
- Oh, he's fading fast.
- And now.
Now they are rebelling.
- What do you advise?
- The children must be
allowed to be children again.
They must learn to play.
They must learn what
it means to have fun.
- [Joel] Everything I know
I learned in kindergarten.
- We need a Santa Claus on Mars.
- Yeah, and you need
a sedative, old man.
(thunder rumbling)
- [Tom] Diarrhea is like
a storm raging inside you.
- Look, uh, you're a busy
man, we'll come back.
Ooh!
- [Joel] Next show at 10:30.
- [Tom] Hey, let's give
it up for the old man.
How about it!
(cheering)
Well, scratch the Chochem idea.
So, you catch any of that?
- Santa Claus on Mars?
- [Joel] I think it would
go something like this.
- Santa Claus.
There's only one Santa
Claus, and he's on Earth.
(laughing)
- Sorry.
- Well, I guess that
takes care of that.
Didn't I tell you it
was a foolish idea
to seek advice
from that old man?
- This is a serious
matter, Voldar,
and desperate problems
require desperate deeds.
- [Joel] Done dirt cheap.
- Earth has had Santa
Claus long enough.
We will bring him to Mars.
- I'm against it!
Our children are fine
the way they are.
I don't want any Santa Claus
bringing them toys and games.
They'll start playing and
laughing and running underfoot.
They'll become a nuisance.
- I've made my decision.
We leave for Earth tonight.
- Pack your other mustache.
- Rigna, Lomas.
- [Tom] Rico,
Youngblood, Dipstick.
(suspenseful music)
Uh-huh.
Okay, thank you, you can lose
this shot now, scene's over.
- [Crow] This is better.
- [Joel] Cricket lighter away!
Cricket lighter.
- [Tom] You know, if they
cancel "Battlestar Galactica",
I'm gonna kill myself.
- Hey, look, their ship
runs on a Simon game.
(Tom beeping)
- [Joel] Stratego!
- [Tom] You sunk my battleship!
- Gentlemen, we can't all be
the Honey Nut Cheerios honeybee.
- Approaching
projected Earth orbit.
- [Joel] I know, I'm the
one that steered us into it.
- Fire portside rockets
number one and number two.
- Portside rockets number
one and number two, fired.
(hissing)
- [Tom] Whoa, lentils, phew.
- Entering Earth orbit.
All right, Voldar, now
to find Santa Claus.
- All right.
- Turn the magnascope
to third power.
(electronic beeping)
We're over a city of some kind.
- [Joel] The Big Apple.
- [Tom] Des Moines?
- So that's what the Earth
people call a city, eh?
How primitive.
- [Tom] Oh, everything's
better on Mars.
- Look at all those
buildings above ground.
Why, we could destroy that city
with one blast of our Q ray.
- We did not come here
to destroy anyone.
Our only purpose is to bring
Santa Claus back to Mars.
- And maybe stop for an
egg cream, but that's it.
- Let's see if we can
locate Santa Claus.
He wears a red suit.
- Mm-hm.
- Trimmed with white fur, and
he has a long white beard.
- Wait a minute, you just
described Huggy Bear.
- It's like looking for
a speck of space dust
in a comet's tail.
- [Tom] Ooh, good analogy.
- Wait a minute, I see him!
I see Santa Claus!
- [Joel] And he's kissing Mommy!
(Tom gasping)
- I see him too!
- He's standing on the
corner ringing a bell.
- No he's not, he's
standing near the entrance
of a large building, next
to a large black kettle.
- He's standing on the
corner, Kimar, he's...
Wait a minute!
I see another one!
- Why, there are hundreds
of Santa Clauses down there!
- Santa is within all of us.
- Just one.
And with so many,
they won't miss one.
Prepare for landing
on next orbit.
- We interrupt our program
with a special bulletin.
- [Tom] I'm Dick York.
- An unidentified
object has been spotted
in orbit around the Earth.
The Soviet Union
denies it has launched
any new space satellites.
- Like they could afford to.
- Our radar stations are
tracking the spaceship,
or whatever it is.
The U.S. Air Force has
alerted all defense commands
and retaliatory units.
- [Joel] You know, I
didn't know the military
had a study hall.
(militaristic music)
- [Tom] Roger, paper
towel rolls are
on the patio table, over.
- But first, a tour
of Paisley Park.
- [Joel] Dear Hair Club for
Men, I need help big time.
Would you consider?
- [Tom] And then a large-scale
bowling pin is put into use.
Morning.
- [Joel] Good morning.
- [Tom] Good morning.
(sighing) Oh boy.
- Wow, there's a ton of
stock footage out there!
- Sir, Earth radar beams
are bouncing off our ship.
- Well, it certainly
took them long enough.
Voldar, turn on
the radar shield.
- Misfunctioning
of radar shield.
- Rigna, check the radar box.
- [Joel] Not the toy
box, the radar box!
- Radar shield functioning.
What was wrong, Rigna?
- A slight case of Dropo.
- [All] Womp-womp-womp-womp!
- I went to the launghing pad
so I could say goodbye to you,
and I remembered!
I've never been to Earth, so
I thought I wanted to see it.
- I may leave you there
in place of Santa Claus.
Now get below, I'll
deal with you later.
- Sorry, Mr. Martian Captain.
Oh, what the hell, the controls!
- [Tom] What, did Sherwood
Schwartz write this?
- [Joel] That's our Dropo.
He'll be back, ha ha!
- Prepare to land.
We'll set down in that
field near the lake.
- [Tom] Neat.
- Rocket silencer set.
- Rotor rockets number
one and two, fire.
(whirring)
- Whoa.
- Lentils.
- [Tom] Ooh.
- All this trouble over a
fat little man in a red suit.
- [Tom] Truman Capote?
- Here's another UFO bulletin.
- [Joel] I'm high.
- The defense department
has just announced
that the unidentified
flying object
has suddenly disappeared
from our radar screens.
- So to hell with it.
- [Tom] Speaking of
disappearing, guys.
- It may be a spaceship
from some other planet
which has the ability to
nullify our radar beams.
Because of the
ominous situation, the
president has ordered
the strategic air
command into action.
- You know, I think
it's kind of, uh,
hot to be wearing
these scarves in here.
- Oh, well the
scarves are a must.
You can't go caroling
without a scarf.
You'll catch your death.
- Yeah, and you were like
one of those kids I remember
in high school that used
to sell the most candy bars
for the marching band.
- President of the
swing choir, too.
- Definitely.
- Thanks, Joel Robinson,
thanks, Tom Servo.
- What a kiss-up, this guy.
- Okay now, if you'll all
look at your sheet music,
we can rehearse my new song.
- You wrote a Christmas song?
- Hey, there's no tradition
like a new tradition.
- Wait a minute, "Let's Have
a Patrick Swayze Christmas?"
- Yeah, yeah, based on my
favorite movie, "Road House."
- Come on, what the
heck does Patrick Swayze
have to do with Christmas?
- Hey, you keep
Christmas in your way
and let me keep
it in mine, okay?
- Oh, geez.
- Come on, Servo, it seems
like a nice enough sentiment.
We can give it a shot, come on.
- All right, okay, okay.
Uh, 12/8 time, key
of A flat major.
Cambot, shoot 'em the tune.
Okay, you'll just have to
stay with me, everybody, okay?
Your parts are written out.
"Let's Have a Patrick Swayze
Christmas" by Crow T. Robot.
(clearing throat)
- Paul, let's have a
Patrick Swayze Christmas.
- Right, hit it, Cambot.
(mellow music)
- Oh, oh, I start, I get it.
Okay, pick it up.
♪ Open up your heart and let the
Patrick Swayze Christmas in ♪
♪ We'll gather at the road
house with our next of kin ♪
- Not bad.
♪ And Santa can be our
regular Saturday night thing ♪
♪ We'll decorate a bar stool
and gather 'round and sing ♪
♪ Oh let's have a Patrick
Swayze Christmas this year ♪
♪ Or we'll tear your throat
out and kick you in the ear ♪
- Hold it, hold it,
Cambot, stop it.
Crow, I don't know
if I think this is
an appropriate sentiment
any more for Christmas.
- Hey, what, like a
good action sequence
don't belong at Christmas?
- Well, no, it's just
that I've never heard of
an action sequence in a
Christmas carol before.
- Well then, grab
hold of your socks
and read on, Joel Robinson!
- Okay, pick it up from
measure 20, Cambot.
(mellow music)
Lovely intro though,
very tasteful.
- Thank you.
- I like that.
♪ It's my way or the highway
this Christmas at my bar ♪
♪ I'll have to smash
your kneecaps ♪
♪ If you bastards touch my car ♪
♪ I got the word that Santa has
been stealing from the till ♪
♪ I think that that
right jolly old elf ♪
♪ Better make out his will ♪
♪ Oh let's have a Patrick
Swayze Christmas one and all ♪
♪ And this can be the haziest ♪
(lively piano solo)
- Whoa.
- Ooh.
♪ This can be the laziest ♪
(lively piano solo)
♪ This can be the Swayziest
Christmas of them all ♪
♪ La la la la la la ah-ha ♪
- How long before it
becomes a standard?
- I think you gotta
come with me, come on.
(shouting)
- We'll be right back.
Save a leg for me.
(mellow music)
- Fire retro rockets
number five and six.
- I got a million of 'em.
- Retro rockets
five and six, fired.
(whirring)
- Yep, lentils.
- Lentils.
- Pretty much.
- Yeah.
- [Joel] Uh, polka dots
and moonbeams, sir.
(beeping)
- Get that, would ya?
- Lower landing legs.
- I've got the landing legs.
- [Joel] Real sophisticated
space leg controls, I like that.
- [Tom] He loves his work.
- [Joel] Gosh, he's
good at that thing.
- [Tom] Yep.
- Landing legs lowered.
- Attention, crew,
this is Kimar.
- Today's blue
light special is--
- Rigna, Voldar and I will
leave the ship to investigate.
- [Joel] Stinky,
Softbatch, Clamdip.
- And Dropo will stay on
board on constant alert
for immediate blast-off.
- [Tom] There.
(dramatic music)
(imitating engine noises)
- [Tom] Ooh, getting roasted.
- [Announcer] The Defense
Department believes
that the object spotted on--
- Ah, Splendor in the Leaves.
- [Tom] Mm-hm.
- [Announcer] Nothing more
than a meteor which burned up
when it entered our atmosphere.
Professor Werner von Green,
our leading space expert.
- [Tom] Is this a Bergman
film all of a sudden?
- [Announcer] Stay tuned
for further bulletins.
- Wish we had parents
instead of this radio.
- Billy, what does
a Martian look like?
- I dunno, nobody's
ever seen one.
- [Joel] What's Vietnam?
- I don't believe
there are any Martians.
- You don't, huh?
What would you do if a Martian
walked right up behind you?
- I'd scream.
- Hey, how ironic!
I'm a victim of circumstance.
- Aw, stop it, Betty,
I'm trying to sleep.
- I see a Martian.
♪ Hello ♪
- Come on, let's go home.
- [Tom] I'll lie
there with the, huh?
- Who, who are you?
- We're from Mars.
Don't be afraid.
We have children just
like you on Mars.
- [Joel] Only
they're worse actors.
- What are those funny things
sticking out of your heads?
- Those are our antennae.
- Are you a television set?
- No, but I play one on TV.
- Stupid question.
Is this what you want to
do to our children on Mars?
Turn them into
nincompoops like these?
- Hold your tongue, Voldar.
(mumbling)
What's your name, little boy?
- Who's your daddy?
- Billy, Billy Foster, sir.
And this is my sister Betty.
- Perhaps you can
help us, Billy.
- And Betty.
- We're looking for one
of your Santa Clauses.
- [Billy] There's
only one Santa Claus.
- We've seen many of
them in your cities.
- Oh, those are his helpers.
There's only one
real Santa Claus,
and he's in his workshop
up at the North Pole.
- That's what we came
here to find out.
- Oh great, kid, you just
fingered Kris Kringle.
- Come on, you two.
- Let me go!
- [Billy] Where
are you taking us?
- Leave them alone, Voldar!
- What, and leave them here
to inform the authorities?
- He's right, Kimar,
we better take them
along with us to the North Pole.
- Very well, come along.
(dramatic music)
- [Tom] Ooh, Maynard Ferguson
playing a ballad there.
- This morning, two children
disappeared mysteriously
from the vicinity of Welch Lake.
The police have found no
clues, and it seems as though
Billy and Betty Foster have
simply vanished into thin air.
This appears to be a
day when everything
is vanishing into thin air.
- Including a few
frames of the film.
- The armed forces are
continuing their search
for the mysterious
object from space.
(ominous music)
- [Tom] And now,
for your enjoyment,
some suggestive scenes
of jets refueling.
(gasping)
- [Joel] All done in there?
- Why do you think
they call him Dropo?
- All right, Billy and Betty.
Nobody's here, come on in.
- Golly!
- [Tom] Uh, yeah, I pretty
much run this place.
- Now, I'm not supposed
to bring you here.
The chief's gonna be
awful mad if he finds us.
- Boy, wait'll the
kids at home find out
that I was in a real
Martian spaceship.
- Oh, it's all about
appearances, isn't it.
- No, don't touch anything!
Here.
That's the
antigravity generator.
And these--
- [Tom] Are meaningless.
- Are the retro rockets.
- Oh.
- Does this light up?
- Only when radar waves
are bouncing off our ship.
Then we put up
this radar screen.
Then nobody can
find us in space.
- Boy, that's pretty sharp.
- Yep.
- What's this, Dropo?
- Oh, that's the
elevator signal.
That light starts
flashing when somebody's
coming up from the
navigation deck.
- [All] Doh!
- Wow, Liz Taylor's
wedding ring.
- [Joel] It's the Hope Diamond.
Hoped it was real.
- No, no no no, don't!
There's no time for that!
- [Joel] (laughing) Oh,
Dropo, you've done it again!
- [Tom] You knucklenut.
Doo da doo da doo.
- Nothing, nothing, no kids
in the radar box, ha ha, no.
(clearing throat)
- [Joel] Drop 'em, Dropo.
- Thinking of taking another
nap in the radar box, Dropo?
- No, s-s-sir.
As a matter of fact, I
was just looking in there
to remind myself never
to hide in there again.
(laughing)
- I bet.
- [Tom] You know, you're the
Gilligan of your time, Dropo.
- [Rigna] Approaching
north pole.
- Ooh, that was suspenseful.
- I can see Santa
Claus' workshop.
- [Tom] Rosebud.
(imitating breaking glass)
- Let's prepare for landing.
Hargo, set the rocket silencers.
Dropo.
- Yes, sir.
- You stay aboard and
guard those children.
(Tom laughing idiotically)
They must not
leave the ship now.
- Now?
- [Tom] Is the winter of
our discontent, made glo--
- What do you mean, Voldar?
- If we take them
with us to Mars,
Santa's disappearance
will remain a mystery.
No one on Earth will ever
know that Santa Claus
was kidnapped by Martians.
- [Joel] Do you realize
what you just said?
- [Tom] I don't think so.
- Perhaps you're right.
Dropo.
- Drop 'em.
- Get back to those children,
and don't let them out of
your sight, understand?
- Yes, sir, I understand.
I'll keep an eye on 'em.
- And now Red in
The Silent Spot.
(Tom humming lighthearted music)
- [Tom] Oh man.
- We've landed.
- [Joel] I guess we'll have
to take your word for it.
- Secure the ship.
Lomas, you remain
on guard and have
the ship ready for
immediate blast-off.
- 'Cause we've landed.
- Rigna, Hargo, Voldar.
- [Tom] Skeeter,
Buzzbomb, Ringja.
- Activate Torg.
- Torg?
- Torg, time for go to bed.
- To capture a roly poly
little man like Santa Claus?
We don't need Torg.
- We won't take any chances.
Come, nothing can stop Torg.
- [Tom] Torg?
- [Joel] That
one's full-figured.
- [Tom] Come on,
Cindy, I mean, Skipper.
Oh heck, this shot has been in
so many sitcoms, I'm confused.
- They're going to
kidnap Santa Claus.
And us too.
- They came to rob Las Vegas.
- Not if we can help it.
We've got to get out
of here and warn Santa.
- What's a Torg?
- I don't know, but
I'm not afraid of him.
- Oh, he's in denial.
- He's not going to stop us.
Come on.
Wait, Betty.
- [Tom] I forgot
my testosterone.
- [Joel] Now they can't watch
Nick at Nite.
- Why did you do that?
- If this ship
ever leaves Earth,
they'll have the whole U.S.
Space Force after them.
Come on.
Wait a minute.
- [Tom] Now what?
- What's he gonna do, pull
the distributor cap off?
- There.
- Come on.
- [Tom] Kid's the
MacGyver of his time.
(mellow music)
(ominous music)
(bell ringing)
- Oh, "Jacob's Ladder,"
the lost scenes.
- [Joel] Oh, they shot this
in Minnesota in October.
- [Tom] Got that look to it.
- Apparently that spaceship's
a lot bigger on the inside.
- [Tom] Like a TARDIS.
- [Joel] Well, at least they're
dressed for the North Pole.
- Yeah, what is
it, about 91 below?
- [Tom] I'd say
this is symbolic of
the unconscious of
the lower nature.
It's very Jungian, I'd say.
(Tom humming dramatic music)
- [Joel] Monkey
Patrol, in color.
(wind whooshing)
You know, these are
like cheap versions
of the "Lost in Space" sets.
(Tom chuckling)
- [Tom] Say!
Oh, it's him.
Well, still.
- Oscar Wilde 2000.
- This action must
take place swiftly.
We can't afford to
make any mistakes.
Hargo, you cover the
rear of the workshop.
Rigna, Voldar.
- [Joel] Ringworm,
Crankcase, Lubejob.
- I'll direct Torg.
- Voldar isn't here.
- Rigna, go up and tell Voldar--
- [Tom] Why, Voldar,
you've been crying.
- Voldar, this is another
one of your delaying tactics.
You've been opposing
me at every turn,
and now I'm warning you,
change your attitude.
- I'm warning you,
- Are you finished, Chief?
- Yes I am, and you will be
too, if you're not careful.
- Oh, but I am careful, Chief.
- [Tom] Don't call me chief!
- So careful that I
looked in on the children
before I left the ship.
- You stay away
from those children.
- That will be easy to do.
They've escaped.
- Voldar, if this is
your idea of a joke--
- Ask Dropo.
- I'm funny, just ask him.
- They overheard our plans.
At this very moment,
they're on their way
to Santa Claus to warn him.
- It's true, Kimar.
Their footprints.
- Hm, child tracks.
Two, three days old.
- We must stop them.
Those children mustn't
reach Santa Claus!
Follow them, I'll put
Torg on their trail.
- [Tom] I want those kids dead,
I want Santa's house
burned to the ground!
- Torg, come out
of the spaceship.
Torg, come out of the spaceship.
- [Joel] Torg, don't make
me come into that spaceship.
(eerie music)
- Uh, Betty, have you ever
read the book "Alive"?
- Billy, I can't run any more.
I'm cold.
(hissing)
And I'm tired.
And it's beginning to snow.
- [Tom] It's beginning to
look a lot like Christmas.
- Try, we've got to warn Santa.
We can't stop now.
They might catch us.
- Where is Santa?
- Sleeping it off.
- I don't know.
His workshop must be
somewhere around here.
- [Tom] All of a sudden
this is "To Build a Fire."
- Betty, look!
It's Voldar!
- [Joel] No, that's Creamhorn
over there.
- He's the mean one.
The one who doesn't like us.
- Oh, who wouldn't
like you, princess?
- [Tom] Yeah, please.
- [Joel] "Ice Station
Zebra," the early years.
- [Tom] It looks like Eric
Heiden gone horribly wrong.
- Ah, watch this,
I'm flipping him off!
- [Tom] Sh!
- [Joel] What is this,
the end of "The Shining?"
- [Tom] Oh, you have
got to be kidding me!
(laughing)
(bear growling)
- Suzy Chapstick,
the early years.
- [Joel] Hey, check it
out, there's a stupid guy
in a goofy bear
costume out here!
- Why did he run away?
- [Tom] What's Vietnam?
- I don't know.
- [Betty] Uh-oh!
- It's Santa Bear!
- [Joel] Quick, in here
where we can be cornered.
(bear growling)
(Tom humming dramatic music)
- Ah, same to you, squirt.
- [Tom] I can see the head
piece draped over the body.
What kind of a bear?
- [Joel] Look,
shouldn't you be in
"Holiday on Ice" or something?
- [Tom] Allo allo allo allo.
- Ah, forget it.
(bear roaring)
Hm, must be an adenoid problem.
- Don't move, Betty.
I'll go take a look.
- [Tom] I think the coast is...
Thunk, oh no, his head must've
gone about 75 feet, woo-hoo!
- It's all right
now, Betty, come on.
- I'm cold.
- And unfeeling.
- I wish it wouldn't snow.
- That's the best thing
that could happen.
It'll cover our tracks,
and be harder for the
Martians to find us.
- [Joel] And we'll freeze to
death and be little kidsicles.
- And it will be hard for
us to find Santa's workshop.
I'm scared.
- We'll find it.
Which way is north?
- [Tom] First we'll make contact
with the Norwegian underground.
- I see it, I see
it, Santa's workshop!
- [Joel] No, that's the
Children's Television Workshop.
- Right there!
See the lights?
- Where?
The lights are moving.
(dramatic music)
- [Joel] Isn't that the
"Jeopardy!" theme song
done in a minor key?
(humming ominous music)
- They're coming towards us.
- Betty, that's
not Santa's house.
- [Tom] That's my wife,
ba-boom, thank you.
- [Betty] What is it?
- [Joel] It's a guy
in a cardboard box
with a coffee urn on his head.
- Hey, it's the robot
that walked from Hawaii
to Gilligan's Island.
- [Joel] What a
dopey-looking robot, man.
The polar bear was a
lot better than that.
- Booth or table?
- [Tom] It was after
the apocalypse.
No one was prepared for
the robot holocaust.
- [Joel] Aw, come here,
ya little ragamuffins, ah.
- Now destroy them, crush them!
- You were adopted.
- Crush them, Torg!
Do as I say!
- Voldar, I knew you'd
try something like this.
I set Torg's controls
so he will obey only me.
Release them, Torg!
- Oil can, oil can!
- You are very lucky.
Now don't try to escape again.
You may not be so
lucky next time.
Hargo, take them
back to the ship,
lock them up, and rejoin us.
- You won't get away with
this, you, you Martians!
- Santa's gonna cut you, man!
Santa's a blade man, man!
- The danger grows
with every minute.
- As does my love.
- Let's get Santa
Claus and blast off.
We'll surround the workshop
and send Torg in to get Santa.
Nobody is to be harmed
unless they get in our way.
- Bah.
- [All] Humbug.
- No one is to be harmed.
What has happened to the
great warriors of our planet?
Mars used to be
the planet of war!
- [Tom] War, huh,
what is it good for?
- Mark my words, Kimar.
Your softness will destroy us.
- [Joel] Your Downy softness.
- Santa Claus, toys,
games, laughing children.
- Well, we shall see.
But for now, to your posts!
- VFW Post 309!
- Torg, follow me!
(dramatic music)
- [Tom] Walk this way!
- If I could walk that way, I
wouldn't be wearing the box.
- [Tom] Ba-bing!
(all shouting)
- [Joel] What does that say,
"No shirt, no
shoes, no service?"
- [Tom] (chuckling)
Smoke free my Aunt Fanny!
Ho ho ho!
- Get him, Torg.
- Exterminate with
extreme prejudice!
- [Tom] Whoa, we're outta here.
- [Joel] Knock knock.
(mellow music)
- Man, this "Santa Claus
Conquers the Martians"
is really depressing.
It makes it really feel
like Christmas, ho ho no.
- Yeah, I feel jolly,
just like old St. Nick.
Ho ho ho ho ho ho.
- Ricky, get me a scotch,
I'm suffering from
Christmas depression!
- Hey, you guys.
- Joel, Joel, couldn't we
see a more cheerful movie,
like maybe "The
Sorrow and the Pity"?
- Well, I got that
all covered, you guys.
I tricked Frank into sending
up a bunch of movies up here.
- Wow!
- And it's something
we can watch after
the experiment.
Let's see, we got "Grinch
Who Stole Christmas."
- Are you sure that's not "The
Fish Who Saved Pittsburgh?"
- Yes, my little
huckleberry friend.
We also got "Mr. Magoo's
Christmas Carol."
- No, Jim Backus lives!
- And "Frosty the Snowman."
- "Frosty the Snowman", Jackie
Vernon did not die in vain!
(cheering)
- Right, we've got Rankin Bass'
"Rudolph the
Red-Nosed Reindeer."
- All right, Burl Ives died
so that we may enjoy the--
- Hey, uh, he's not dead.
- Oh, sorry, Burl.
- Yeah, and then we've got
"A Charlie Brown Christmas."
- Oh boy, I love that
one, especially the part
where they eat all those
Dolly Madison cakes.
You know, Koo Koos,
Zingers, Razzies.
- Wait a second, wait a minute.
Those were the commercials.
Actually, without the
Dolly Madison commercials,
the entire show is about
nine minutes long, okay?
We got a few others here.
We've got "It's a
Wonderful Life."
- Wow, really great!
- I love that one!
- Well, don't get too excited,
it's the lame Marlo
Thomas version.
- Shame on you, Marlo.
- We also got "Miracle
on 34th Street."
(cheering)
No, no, it's the
David Hartman one.
- Shame on you guys.
- We got a few
others here, though,
it's kinda going to the
bottom of the bag here,
kind of some low-budget ones.
"The Christmas that
Totally Ruled,"
it's about a
curmudgeonly old man
that learns the true
meaning of Christmas.
- Fresh idea!
- We have "The Christmas
That Wasn't That Bad,"
which is about a
curmudgeonly old woman
who learns the true
meaning of Christmas.
And then there's "The Christmas
That Really Kicked Ass,"
which is about a
curmudgeonly old man
and a curmudgeonly
old woman that learns
the true meaning of Christmas.
- Oh, that would be--
(alarm buzzing)
- Ah, we got movie sign!
(all shouting)
- [Tom] Now we've gotta
come back and watch this?
- [Joel] Oh boy.
- Sorry, we just waxed.
- No one's allowed
- [Joel] My spine!
(imitating cracking)
- [Santa] You're the
biggest toy I've ever seen!
- [Tom] I could
use a toy like you.
Ah.
- And very well-made, too.
- [Tom] Nice ash can.
- By the great dog star,
Santa's treating him like a toy!
- [Joel] Oh, he treats
everyone like that.
- Get him, Torg, grab him!
- He's become a toy.
- Rigna, we'll have to
get Santa ourselves.
Come on, Voldar.
(suspenseful music)
- [Tom] Nobody expects
the Spanish Inquisition!
- What have we here?
More toys?
- Those are Martians!
- Santa Claus, you're
coming with us.
- [Joel] You're coming to town.
- No, you can't take him now!
It's too near Christmas!
- Quiet, you.
- But.
- [Joel] Oh, he
stopped them short.
- We don't want to
hurt you, Santa Claus,
so come along quietly.
- How are you gonna hurt
him with a hair dryer?
- [Joel] Hey, lawn jockey.
Just kidding.
- Why?
Why did you have to
do that to my helpers?
- It's harmless, it will
wear off in a short while.
- [Tom] It's just a
Wham-O Air Blaster.
- Well, why didn't you
say so in the first place?
- Now, you come with us.
We need you on Mars.
- Noonan!
- You moved.
Hm.
- Are you sure this is harmless?
- Oh, I never saw
such lazy people.
Standing around like statues.
There's work to be done!
Let's get to it.
- [Tom] The Twilight Zone.
- Oh me oh my, oh me, oh my.
- [Tom] Down by the bayou.
- Mrs. Claus is going to
be very angry about this.
- She's gonna hit me
with a frying pan.
- Torg, take him!
Obey my commands!
- Forget it, Kimar.
- [Tom] He's not house trained.
- Rigna was right.
He's nothing but a toy now.
Best to leave him here.
- Believe me, I had nothing
whatsoever to do about this.
- Oh, that's what you always say
when you're drinking
with your friends.
- I can't recall a time when
you were so silent for so long.
- Let's go, old man!
- Old man, take a look at my
elf, I'm a lot like you, woo!
(dramatic music)
- [Joel] Next week
on "Barnaby Jones,"
"Mrs. Claus of Death."
(gasping)
- [Tom] Village Voice,
Santa's Outing, what?
- And Mrs. Santa Claus
has positively identified
the kidnappers as Martians.
Never in the history
of mankind have
the nations of the
world reacted with such
unanimity and cooperation.
Tonight, the lights
will burn until dawn
in the United Nations building,
as the leaders of the world
map a course of action.
- [Joel] Give
sanctions more time!
- And, at Cape Kennedy, our
correspondent interviewed
Werner Von Green,
the man in charge.
- I'm innocent, I was
only following orders!
Oh. (imitating cracking)
- Mr. Von Green,
what is the Space
Agency doing about this?
- Well, they have mobilized
all the men and equipment
in our starship project.
- [Joel] What is that,
the Groucho duck up there?
- And we have rushed
our astronauts into
an intensive program for the
final phase of our training.
♪ Boom shadow, boom shadow ♪
- Our starship is
supposed to undergo
six months of test flights,
but we are going to
forget about the testing and
go after those Martian monkeys.
- [Announcer] Isn't that risky?
- [Tom] It will not be
difficult, Mein Fuhrer!
- But every one of
our astronauts is
begging for the chance
to go after the Martians.
Who wouldn't give everything
to bring Santa back
to our children?
- Me!
- Over here!
(suspenseful music)
- [Tom] Hi, I'm Bonnie at NASA.
- Before this decade is out,
we will bring Santa
back from Mars.
- [Tom] Remember this one?
"I said lunch, not launch!"
- Oh, "Far Out Space Nuts."
- Yeah.
- "Capricorn One" will
return after this.
(Tom humming lively music)
- [Joel] So it, uh, just
keeps going up like that, huh.
- Yep.
- Mm-hm.
- Fat bald men are
quickly mobilized.
- [Joel] So really,
that's really just,
kinda keeps heading for the sky.
- [Tom] That's pretty
much what it does, yeah.
- [Joel] Just keeps, onward
and upward like that.
- [Tom] Ooh, three
stars by her name.
Earth girls are easy.
- Earth hasn't reacted yet.
- No radar beams being
bounced off our ship.
Looks like we made
a clean getaway.
(laughing)
- Here I sit, broken, which
one of you clowns wrote that?
- He's having the
time of his life.
He's such a funny little man.
Why, I've only been with
him for five minutes,
and he has me laughing
just like an Earthling.
What's soft and round,
and you put it on a stick,
and you toast it in a fire?
- [Tom] An elf?
- And it's green.
- Oh, a dead elf.
- I don't know, what?
- A Martianmallow!
(laughing)
- [Joel] You just heard that?
Geez.
- That's what
you're all becoming.
Martianmallows.
Soft.
- Absorbent.
- Weak.
That old man is a menace.
- [Santa] And it was a
very foggy Christmas Eve.
- [Tom] So it was '69, I
was stationed in Phnom Penh.
Charlie had us
pinned down the way.
The only thing that kept
me going was Laotian gold
we got in Saigon.
- I tell you, it was the biggest
chimney I'd ever been in.
And then suddenly--
- [Joel] Suddenly Sally.
- Suddenly I realized it
wasn't a chimney at all.
It was the smokestack
of the Queen Elizabeth.
- [Tom] Ha.
Santa, you're just about
as funny as a train wreck.
- Don't you think
that was funny?
- [Betty and Billy] Yes, Santa.
- [Joel] It's just
that we're Norwegian.
- Well, why didn't you laugh?
- Gee, Santa, it's
all our fault.
We told them where to find you.
- Oh, balderdash and
a fiddle-dee-dee.
- Whoa, language,
Santa, language!
- Everybody knows
where Santa lives.
Besides, I've always
wanted to visit Mars.
(all laughing idiotically)
- Mommy and Daddy are
going to be angry.
- You think that's something?
I can just see Mrs. Claus now.
Christmas coming,
and I'm not there.
She'll have a fit.
- The elves have learned
how to handle her, though.
- Oh me oh my oh me.
- [Tom] By the bayou.
- Come and get it, dinnertime!
- Here's Dropo!
If I can't cheer
you up, Dropo can.
He always makes me laugh.
- You'll have a
wonderful dinner tonight.
Oh, there's soup,
and, and beef stew,
and chocolate ice cream.
- And Spam?
- No thank you, Dropo.
I'm not hungry.
- Come on, Billy.
Ooh, well, is it all right if
I have your chocolate ice cream?
- Sure.
- Oh, I just love
chocolate ice cream.
- [Joel] You know,
that Dropo plays it
a little broader
than Larry Storch.
- Yep.
- Mm-hm.
What a pig he is.
- Gee, Mars must be a
terrible place to live.
Some chocolate ice cream.
- Pills for dinner!
- Ho ho, what are
we, Judy Garland?
- I suppose if a
Martian has a headache,
he doesn't take pills, he
takes chocolate ice cream.
- [Joel] Ah, that's
not too funny, Santa.
You're getting a light.
- Oh dear, oh dear.
- [Tom] You've been
a great audience.
- Kimar, look at this!
That small blip is not an
asteroid, it's a spaceship,
and it's on our tail.
It's getting closer.
- Impossible, Rigna.
They couldn't have spotted us,
we have our radar shield on.
- I know that, sir, but
they are gaining on us.
- Is it possible Earth
has a secret device
that can penetrate
our radar shield?
- They have a secret device,
and his name is Billy Foster.
- [Tom] Billy Foster
is The Secret Device.
- They'll destroy
us if we allow them!
- [Joel] Oh, adjust
your sash, Carl.
- I won't allow it.
- Oh no, he's gonna sing!
- [Tom] Ugh, yuck.
- I think we underestimate
the resourcefulness
of these Earth people.
- [Tom] I sure hope
that's pudding.
- Very clever of the boy.
Make your repairs, Rigna.
I'll take evasive action.
- [Joel] Time for some fun.
- Well.
- [Tom] Thunk, ooh!
- How is Santa, and
the little Earthlings?
My, it must be tiresome,
cooped up in this little room.
- Yeah, but it's
only $18 a night.
- Say, how would you like
to see the rest of the ship?
- [Joel] Bite me.
- You're not fooling
me, you don't like us.
- You're mean.
- Oh, come on, now,
that's not true.
- [Tom] Well.
- Why, Santa makes everyone
feel good, even me.
- I don't trust you.
- Now now, Billy boy.
- Grease him, Santa!
- That's not the
Christmas spirit.
- Ah, I'm Jewish, Santa.
- Why, of course, Voldar.
We'd love to take
the grand tour.
- [Tom] Follow my lead,
Billy, I'm packin' heat.
- [Joel] I want to
be alone with Santa.
- [Tom] Nice take to
the camera, thank you.
What a clown.
- [Joel] Oh, that must be
the laundry cute over there.
- [Tom] Why are
things in English?
- This room is called the--
- Air lock.
- [Joel] Same to you, woodleg!
- That's right.
- Sure, this is
where you come when
you're ready to go out in space.
It's airtight.
You put on your space suit,
and go out through that door.
- So if you wanted
to kill somebody,
send 'em out, ahh!
- And they pump air back
into the room through there.
When it reaches the pressure
of the rest of the ship,
you can take your
space suit off.
- [Tom] Who is this kid,
Ira Flatow all of a sudden?
- Where is the control
that opens the door, sir?
- Not here.
That's in the control deck.
You see, once you pull that
switch, the warning bell sounds,
and in 60 seconds,
that door opens.
- That's to give a
space man a chance
to make a final checkup
on their equipment.
There's no air out in space.
If that door were open now,
it would pull all the air out
of this room, and us with it.
- [Voldar] You certainly
know a great deal
about space travel, son.
- [Joel] I like you, that's
why I'm going to kill you last.
- Maybe sooner than that.
(gasping)
(Tom laughing evilly)
- [Joel] I'm gone,
presto, va-voom.
- Santa, that clock's stopped.
- 60 seconds, that
must be the door timer.
- Have you two ever
seen a grown man scream?
Santa's gonna whimper
like a whipped pup.
- Santa, he locked us in!
- Oh, I don't think so.
He probably just stepped
out for a moment.
- [Tom] You're living
in denial, Santa!
Wake up and smell the coffee!
- He's not like
Kimar and the others.
- I don't like him.
- I'm worried, Santa.
- Now, now, children,
let's not get excited.
- Help, help!
- [Joel] Now, what
would McGyver do?
- [Tom] This is great,
this is gonna be great!
Watch!
(suspenseful music)
- It's Voldar!
He's going to open
the space door!
Help, Kimar!
- Billy, please, now
you're embarrassing me.
- Kimar, help!
- [Joel] This is my time.
I feel good about me.
- [Tom] Come on!
I admire the plucky kid.
He really thinks on his
feet, a real booster.
- Stella!
- Gee, Santa, what
are we going to do?
Once the door opens, we
haven't got a chance.
- [Tom] We'll die a
horrible asphyxiated death.
- Where did you say
this leads to, Billy?
- Seven.
- Mississippi.
- Six.
- Five.
- Mississippi.
- [Tom] Connecticut.
- Four.
- Noonan.
- [Tom] Massachusetts.
- Three.
- Mississippi.
- Two.
- Feelin' good.
- One, zero.
- Ah, oh.
- Who's in the air lock?
- No one, now.
(gasping)
- What's going on, Voldar?
- Chief, Santa and the
children are missing!
- [Tom] I love you!
- It'll never work!
- Drifting around in space.
Along with the rest
of the space junk.
- My mother was junk,
don't talk like that!
- [Tom] (humming
dramatic music) Pow!
Boom, pow, zing, boof, choke!
- [Joel] Oh, he's fighting
the cameraman now.
- [Tom] Now we're in trouble.
- When I'm through
with you, Voldar,
you'll wish you were
floating out there in space!
(Santa laughing)
- Merry Christmas, everybody!
- Ah, Mr. Claus, you have
a nasty habit of surviving.
- Santa Claus, you're all right!
I thought you were--
- Well, when Voldar accidentally
left us in the airlock,
and then came up
here and accidentally
threw the door switch,
we knew we had to
get out of there
in a hurry, or that
would be the end of us.
- Uh, one, uh, two.
- Accidentally, of course.
- So we crawled out
through the air duct.
- The air duct?
- But the air duct
is just a little--
- Thing with the wheel and the--
(laughing)
- [Tom] Kill him.
- Why, you're talking
to Santa Claus, son.
(laughing)
- [Kimar] But how?
- Well, well now,
you wouldn't want me
to tell my secret, would you?
Oh, poor man.
- [Tom] He's bleeding
from the ears, too bad.
- He looks like someone
who's seen a ghost.
(laughing)
- Get my inhaler and my nitro!
- [Tom] Meanwhile, on the
Salyut 7 space station.
(dramatic music)
- [Joel] It's the Brunswick
bowling ball planet.
(Crow humming fanfare)
- [Kimar] Begin
landing operation.
- Firing retro rockets
one and two, fire.
(hissing)
- Lentils.
- Coulda guessed.
- Lower landing legs.
- [Tom] I said
don't call me legs.
- [Joel] Kevin, this is no
time to use the Nordic Track,
come on, man!
- Lower the ladder.
You and Hargo get
Voldar out of the brig
and take him to
the council room.
He'll stand trial immediately.
- All right, Chief.
- Don't call me Chief!
- We've landed.
- [Tom] You'll have to
take my word for it.
- Hatch open.
- Orrin Hatch.
- Ladder down.
- [Tom] Lauder?
- Power off, ship secure.
- [Tom] Nice Underoos.
♪ Jingle bells, jingle
bells, jingle all the way ♪
♪ Oh what fun it is to ride ♪
- [Joel] Oh, it's
a Tokyo apartment.
- No, it's the guy
from "Deliverance!"
♪ In a one-horse open sleigh ♪
- [Tom] Why are they
wearing Abdominizers?
- Merry Christmas, Voldar.
All right, on your
feet, come on.
(muffled shouting)
- Dropo!
- I was handing the food
pills through the bars,
and he grabbed my hand--
- Shut up!
- [Joel] Oh, you love it.
- Kimar!
- [Tom] When I call my
captain, I touch myself.
- Yes, Rigna.
- [Rigna] Voldar has escaped.
- What?
- He's gone.
- That can only mean trouble.
Put a constant guard on
Santa and the Earth children.
Voldar will be back.
- [Tom] In "Dial M for Martian."
(humming dramatic music)
- [Joel] I'll be out
in a minute, excuse me.
- [Tom] Previously, on "Santa
Claus Conquers the Martians."
- [Joel] Here in Betty
Crocker's test kitchen.
♪ I'll never smile ♪
- [Tom] Oh.
- Mother, is Father here yet?
- No, Bomar, I'll call
you the moment he arrives.
- Is Dropo coming back too?
- Yes, Girmar, now go
back to your studies.
- [Joel] Go play with
your Golden Globe award.
- [Tom] That we bought for you.
(all humming "Dick
Van Dyke Show" theme)
- [Joel] Sh, not now.
- Oh, Kimar!
- Kimar is the savings place.
- [Tom] Headbutt.
- Are you alone?
- No.
- [Momar] Well!
- [Kimar] Earthlings,
Billy and Betty.
- One of each flavor.
- Welcome to our home.
- [All] Headbutt.
Headbutt.
- There's someone else, too.
Come on, come on in!
- [Tom] You may have
to grease the door
for him to get through.
(chuckling) A big ol' haul.
- Ho ho ho!
Lady Momar.
I'm not accustomed to
entering people's homes
through the door, but
you have no chimney.
- [Joel] Breaking and
entering, that's my racket.
- Welcome, Santa
Claus, we hope you'll
make the children
on Mars very happy.
- I'll try, dear lady.
(Tom imitating kissing)
- But I get a per diem.
(mellow music)
- Where are they?
- Well, we'll start
with my youngsters.
How are they, Momar?
- The same.
Quiet, remote, and very unhappy.
They're inside studying.
- [Tom] They've been
reading "The Bell Jar."
- Let old Santa
say hello to them.
And I'm sure these children
would like to meet them.
- I'll tell them you're here.
- [Computer] Y over five.
- [Tom] Tony Danza
is a fine actor.
Sinbad is funny.
Blake Edwards makes
a really good film.
- [Computer] Traveling
along vector A.
- [Joel] You are
powerful, you can sell.
- [Computer] And the
power of 12 megatrons.
- Father, Father, we missed you!
- Ha ha, I missed you too.
- [Tom] I'm fine, Dmitri,
you're fine, we're both fine.
It's good to be fine.
- I've brought some visitors.
From Earth.
Will you come in
please, children?
- [Joel] And sign in, please.
- Billy and Betty, this
is Bomar and Girmar.
- Hi.
- [Joel] Wait, where's
that thing been?
- There's nothing in it.
What are you giving me?
- My hand, to shake.
- [Tom] (buzzing)
Oh, I love that gag.
- [Joel] It's getting
uncomfortable now.
- How old are you?
- I'm 10.
- I'm 10 too, and
Girmar's eight.
- So's my sister.
- [Tom] So's your
sister, and your mother
swims out to troop ships.
- There's another Earth
person that wants to see you.
- [Joel] His name
is B.F. Skinner.
He's going to put
you kids in a box.
(chuckling)
- Dad, get him outta here!
- [Tom] Santa left his
medication at home.
- [Joel] (laughing) Dad, Dad!
(all laughing hysterically)
(screaming)
What is that, an outtake from
"TV's Bloopers and
Practical Jokes?"
- You know, it's
the little things
that can clue you
into drug abuse.
- They're laughing.
Bomar and Girmar, too.
- They've never laughed before.
- Come.
- [Tom] Come on, let's go
catch the end of his act.
He does this killer
drive-up window gag.
(playful music)
- [Joel] He'll be
the first to die.
- Ah, a cave dweller!
No?
- Me, Voldar, hiding
in a dirty cave
like a speckled Mars worm.
Oh, Kimar will get
this, I'll find a way.
- That's easy.
Let's get rid of his little
fat friend in the red suit.
- [Joel] Taffy apple, boss?
Ahh.
- That's suicide.
- [Tom] What do you
mean, whack Santa?
What are you, nuts?
- He's under constant guard.
We couldn't get within 20
feet of him without being--
- [Joel] What is this, a
soliloquy all of a sudden, whoa!
- I have other plans.
(dramatic music)
- Who's playing that?
- Someone's
approaching the cave!
- [Tom] The king approaches!
- It's me, Shim!
- All right.
- Jim?
- [Joel] It's Big Jim McLain.
- All right, Shim, enter.
- Enter, what
happened to come in?
- What did you find out?
- The toy shop is
operating full blast.
No one suspects me.
- Ha-cha!
- So I sneaked down and
took a good long look.
It's nothing like
the one on Earth.
- [Tom] Goodnight, Mrs.
Calabash, wherever you are.
- Kimar has built a
mechanized assembly line
for the old man.
- [Tom] Great Durante.
- Toys are rolling
off by the second.
This planet will be
filled up with toys.
- Well, folks, that was my bit.
I hope youse enjoyed it.
- They got one little toy.
It's the cutest thing.
I's just a coiled spring.
- [Tom] Ooh, ooh,
Muldoon, do you mind?
- It goes down
steps all by itself.
- [Joel] Just like Grandma.
- I was tempted to steal one.
I'd like to fool
around with the thing.
(all groaning)
- Enough with the
Slinky over here!
- The decay is setting in.
It's even affecting you.
Soon all of Martians will
be blithering idiots.
- [Tom] Soon, what
do you mean soon?
- There's no time to lose.
We must go into action.
Now, we cannot
eliminate Santa Claus,
but we can discredit him.
Make him a laughingstock
throughout Mars.
Come on, now listen carefully.
- You, get Donna
Rice on the phone.
I'll get a camera.
- The toy shop
closes at 10 o'clock.
The guards will be
in Kimar's house.
- [Joel] All right, stunt left,
give us a post, and
I'll roll right, got it?
Okay.
(whispering)
- [Tom] Wait a minute,
it's Warhol's Factory!
- Laundry baskets,
kids'll go nuts for 'em!
- Hi, Billy, everything okay?
- Gee, Dropo,
everything's great.
(quirky music)
- [Joel] Wait a minute, does
Mars have any child labor laws?
- [Tom] I don't think so.
- Hundreds and thousands of
letters from all over Mars!
- [Tom] And we got all their
Visa card numbers, too!
Hoo-hoo!
- Ah, war toys, good.
Teaches 'em early
to hate and kill.
- [Tom] Aw, sweet.
- Two dolls, yes, Betty.
- [Tom] Okay, bare down, push!
(breathing heavily)
Bare down, push!
- [Betty] Three baseball bats.
- Three baseball bats.
- And two hard-boiled eggs.
Make that three
hard-boiled eggs.
- [Joel] Oh, those
must be for the LAPD.
- Look at me.
Santa Claus, the great toymaker.
- [Tom] Stuck on a
planet with no booze.
- That's automation for you.
Technology, gee.
Well, that's enough for today.
- Santa makes a poignant
observation on today's society.
- Let's close up shop!
- [Joel] We can still
make it to happy hour!
(all chattering)
- [Tom] Sh!
- Pretty nice, eh?
Lady Momar made it for me.
- Can I try it on, Santa?
(chuckling)
- Don't be silly, Dropo.
This would never fit you.
Why, you have to
fatten up first.
(laughing)
- [Tom] Just, just laugh
at everything he says.
He's easy to provoke.
- Oh great, the, oh, shoot.
For a second I had hope.
- As they say on Earth,
another day, another dollar.
- Well, hello, Santa.
- [Joel] He sounds
like Vincent Price.
- How are you
feeling today, tired?
- No, no, I'm not tired.
But my finger is.
- [Tom] Oh, Santa, no!
It's Christmas!
- It's been pressing buttons
all day long.
- [Joel] That Santa's
one weird mammer jammer.
- I'd better put
my finger to bed.
- Here, children,
here's your milk.
You can play for half an hour,
and then you'll
have to go to bed.
- Daddy, may we watch
the Earth program?
- Certainly, dear, but
only for half an hour.
- The Clarence Thomas
hearings are on.
- Billy?
- Barty?
- Betty?
- Broccoli?
- Don't you want to
watch the Earth programs?
- Oh, no, sir.
We're not interested
in Earth programs.
- They suck.
- I'm going to sleep, goodnight.
- Me too.
- Just a moment.
- Goodnight, Mr. Kimar.
Goodnight, Lady Momar.
- Just a moment, children.
- Don't ever step on my lines!
- Are you feeling well?
- Oh, we feel fine, sir.
Goodnight.
- Goodnight.
- [Kimar] Has someone
been mistreating you?
- Oh no, sir.
You and Lady Momar have
just been swell to us.
Goodnight.
- It's our wages sir, you know,
with what the cost of living is,
and a guy can hardly
make ends meet.
- What could it be, Momar?
They're behaving the way
our children used to behave.
- Can't you tell, Kimar?
They're homesick.
They miss their
parents, their friends.
- [Tom] Nintendo, sugar.
- Kimar, you've got to
send those children back.
- Impossible.
- [Joel] I don't
have the receipt.
- [Tom] Oh my god, he's
playing dressup, no!
- Santa says I gotta fatten up.
Malted milk!
- Yellow moons, pink
hearts, green clovers.
- Chocolate cake!
- Bennies, dexies, X.
- Nowadays, most
people take pills
to lose weight.
- Banana split!
With whipped cream.
- [Joel] And other delights.
- Ooh, that's good pill.
- [Tom] I don't suppose
there's any chance this guy's
gonna end up under the
wheels of a train, is there?
I didn't think so.
- That takes too long.
(gentle music)
- [Joel] He's simple, isn't he?
- Yes, very simple.
- Simple but stupid.
- Hey, that's brilliant!
Santas all over the world
are gonna do that now!
(Tom sighing)
- [Joel] I almost feel like
I shouldn't be watching.
- [Tom] Mm-hm.
- What's with the
Mr. Rogers music?
- [Tom] Uh, so, Lady Momar
made Santa an extra beard?
- Now I'm Santa Claus!
Hoo hoo hoo!
Ho ho ho, Merry
Christmas everyone!
- [Tom] Yeah, we get the idea.
- My finger isn't tired.
- Look out, nose!
- I think I'll go
down to the workshop
and make some more toys.
- [Tom] I gotta go puke.
- [Joel] You know,
somewhere there's a warrant
with his name on
it, I'm sure of it.
♪ Jingle bells, jingle
bells, jingle all the way ♪
(humming "Jingle Bells")
- Okay, everybody got their
Christmas essays ready?
(all talking at once)
Who wants to go first?
- Oh, oh oh oh, ooh, ooh!
- You wanna go first,
you wanna go first?
Oh, Crow, you wanna
go first, buddy?
- Uh, oh, okay, yeah.
Um, uh, "A Christmas
Oratorio," oh, wait.
"A Christmas Editorial,
by Crow T. Robot."
(clearing throat)
- [Tom] Why don't you
just get on with it,
for crying out loud?
- I'm sorry, I was.
(clearing throat)
All right, okay.
"A Christmas Editorial
by Crow T. Robot."
I know I already
said that, um, okay.
"What's the big deal with
Santa's elves, anyway?
"What happens to all
those dumb wooden trains
"and horses and cars?
"No ever kid gets 'em.
"These are the kinda toys
Grandma drags out at Christmas
"to decorate the house,
which smells like her feet
"no matter how much Essence
of Yuletide light bulb
"ring oil she uses,
but I digress.
"No, these are the
real misfit toys.
"They end up in Marshall
Fields window displays
"and FAO Schwartz
catalogs or in overpriced
"little gift shops in Vermont
and Door County, Wisconsin.
"My message is for the elves.
"Gentlemen, what is the problem?
"Why don't we ever see you
in front of a circuit board,
"loading microchips
into a Sega-Vision
"with your little
wooden hammers?
"Elf labor short?
"The good people of Macao are
eager to take your prototypes
"and turn them into
100,000 knockoffs.
"Elves and Santa, take an
example from the Keeblers.
"Now there's some fairies
who know how to market.
"In closing, uh, step out
of the legend days, fellas,
"and join the century
of the Pacific.
"Oh, and uh, Merry
Christmas, the end."
(cheering)
- Good job, Crow!
Okay, who's next, Tom?
- My turn.
- Okay.
- Thank you, Mr. Dough.
Okay, my essay is entitled "A
Child's Christmas in Space."
Let me set the mood here.
Ay-yi-yi-yi-yi, there.
(sighing)
It's quiet in the cold
of our own little orbit,
starless and Bible black.
And as I look down on the big
blue bean we would call home
I think it so near, yet...
Oh, I wish on that
star and I hope that in
a little snow-covered
house with a warm hearth
and a loving family, maybe
some kid is looking up tonight
and wishing upon us.
(gasping)
Oh, and how I hope sweet
Santa will fly by tonight,
because if he does I'm
gonna reach right out
and hug that big guy.
Oh, for the sound
of hooves against
the steel hull of the ship.
Oh, to see the rosy face
of Santa in the portal
offering me a Coke and a smile.
Of course, his face
would be rosy because
it's a vacuum out there, I mean
Santa's heart would explode.
But he won't feel it because
the capillaries in his brain
would pop like
little firecrackers
- Tom.
- Due to the blood
boiling away in his face
like a pudding in a copper.
Oh, the humanity!
And his jolly old belly
would start bubbling like
a roasted marshmallow,
- Tom, whoa.
- Eyes bulging and popping out.
And the reindeer,
oh the reindeer!
Keep floating like
holiday floats
and in turn exploding
- Tom!
In a hail of blood and entrails.
Prancer, boom!
Dancer, boom!
- Tom!
- Hey!
- Hey, Tom!
- Hey, take it easy, Santa's
gonna be okay, buddy.
- Ya sure?
- Yeah, give him a
little credit, okay?
- What a relief.
- All right, now it's my turn.
I wanna do my reading
on Christmas pasts.
- [Tom and Crow] Long past?
- Well, um, yeah, long,
America's past, you know.
Okay, I'm talking about the
'70s Christmas office party.
"Back when a fully
stocked bar was considered
"standard office furniture
and office parties
"were like something out
of a Playboy cartoon.
"Why, the desks would
be overflowing with
"every kind of hard liquor, why,
"there were gallons of
scotch, bourbon, vodka, gin,
"not to mention Galliano,
amaretto, Midori, rye,
"German crock pot gin, you name
it, and sexism was blatant.
"Boy oh boy, you'd find
salesmen groping secretaries
"in the mail room, keys
would be exchanged,
"and although this
was Christmas,
"Jesus was nowhere to be seen."
- Geez, Joel, and you
thought I was bad.
- Yeah, are we really this
cynical about Christmas?
- Well, uh, maybe Gypsy has a
Christmas word for everybody.
(music box playing
"The First Noel")
Well, Merry
Christmas, everybody.
We got commercial
sign over here.
♪ Hello ♪
- Shh, shh!
(quirky music)
- [Joel] Sounds
like the music from
"The Ghost and Mr. Chicken."
- [Voldar] There it is.
- [Tom] Oh, there's
the caution controls.
- Sh!
- What is this, a
Ritz Brothers film?
- [Tom] No, it's better.
(shouting)
Actually, it's Joseph
Biden, Howard Metzenbaum,
and Ted Kennedy like you've
never seen them before.
- [Joel] Now that is
good comedy, that's fun.
- Shim, hold the light.
(groaning)
- [Joel] Boing!
(Tom humming quirky music)
- Ah, this is
gonna shake 'em up.
These toys will never
be the same again.
- Sh!
- Oh, I hate this.
- Someone's coming.
Quick, down!
- [Tom] Something
stupid this way comes.
♪ Jingle all the way ♪
- Uh, Ed Grimley's here.
♪ Oh what fun it is to ride
in a one-horse open sleigh ♪
- [Joel] Take him out, now!
- What a break,
it's Santa Claus!
- And he's loaded!
- He's alone, no guards.
♪ Jingle bells, jingle
bells, jingle all the way ♪
- [Tom] Kill him, please.
♪ Oh what fun it is to ride ♪
(dramatic music)
- Meanwhile, back at
the Gum Disease Caverns.
- [Joel] All right, Santa, sing.
- Now stay put, my
fat little friend.
- Hey Santa, how do
you like this toy?
- Ho ho ho.
- My friend asked you
a question, answer him!
- Ho ho ho.
- Quiet, Shim.
Put on the nuclear curtain.
- [Tom] Then put
on The Carpenters.
I love them.
- Tomorrow marks the end
of Operation Santa Claus.
And Mars returns to normal!
(laughing)
- Dropo!
Dropo, you rascal,
where are you?
- [Joel] Opal?
- Dropo!
- Oh, Dropo.
Drop 'em.
- Children, breakfast is ready.
- Good morning, dear.
- Kimar, I can't find Dropo.
- Hey, what, no
headbutt this morning?
Honeymoon over?
- What is he up to now?
- Good morning!
- Yeah, whatever.
- Good morning, Lady Momar.
Oh, oh, my extra suit, the one
you made for me, is missing.
- [Tom] And that
extra beard, too.
- I'm sure I brought it home
from the toy shop last night.
- That's two things that are
missing, your suit and Dropo.
- What, oh, oh, ha
ha, that explains it.
When you find my missing suit,
you'll find Dropo inside it.
He's out someplace
playing Santa Claus.
- I'll take care of him.
- Oh, no, no.
- [Tom] Plug him between
the eyes for me, will ya?
- He's probably at the
toy shop making toys.
- He's probably at the bar.
- He loves it.
- Children, would
you please hurry?
Breakfast is ready!
- Yes, yes, if you don't hurry,
your breakfast will get cold.
- [Joel] I think Santa's
slipped off the roof.
- [Tom] Oh, irony. (chuckling)
- Dropo, we're here!
- [Tom] Here's Johnny!
- He's hiding, Santa.
- Oh, playing hide and seek, eh?
All right, Dropo, here
we come, ready or not!
- This is not a game, Santa!
He could be seriously hurt!
Everything's a joke with you.
- He's not here, Santa!
- That's funny.
Oh, well, he'll turn up.
Let's get started.
(chuckling)
Hey, oh, Betty?
Okay, let's go.
- One teddy bear and one doll.
- And a submachine gun.
- One teddy bear.
And one doll.
- Ho-ho, that's right,
reindeer breath.
- Santa, stop the machine!
Look!
- The doll as a
teddy bear's head
and the teddy bear
has a doll head!
- [Tom] No problem, we'll
give 'em to dyslexic kids.
- Let's try it again.
What's next, Betty?
- One baseball bat.
- [Tom] Oh look, they made
a Prince Vortex racquet.
- A baseball tennis racquet?
Why, this will never do!
- We'll have to sell
this stuff to Wham-O!
- Oh dear, what else, Betty?
- A toy train.
- [Joel] Looks like Santa's
doing sound for Yes.
- [Tom] And a fetal pig,
no, no, stop the machine!
Oh, it's growing hair and
teeth, look at that thing.
- This doesn't make sense.
- Thank you, Santa.
- This never happened
when we made toys by hand.
- Oh, everything's
better by hand.
Go to bed, old man.
- Something very strange
is happening here.
- [Joel] Something
is wrong on Saturn 3.
- I think you'd better
call your father.
- [Tom] A weenie.
(laughing) That's
my little joke.
- Father.
- Yes, son?
- Father, this is Bomar.
- [Kimar] Yes, Bomar?
- [Joel] A little burro.
- Father, we're in the toy shop.
Dropo wasn't here,
and there's something
wrong with the toy machine, too.
- I want braces.
- Yee-haw.
- It's time to go.
Shim, wake up!
(Tom imitating thunking)
- I still think you're
making a mistake.
It's too dangerous, walking
right into the enemy camp.
- Kimar and his men wouldn't
dare lay a finger on us.
Not while we're keeping
Santa Claus a hostage.
Now, if we're not back in three
hours, you know what to do.
- [Tom] Go ahead and
order without us.
- Open the nuclear curtain!
- Either these nuclear
curtains go, or I do.
- Hey, it's the Bugaloos.
- Ooh.
- [Joel] Uh-oh.
- Just a word of warning.
If you got any big
ideas, forget 'em.
If you walk through
that nucular curtain,
you'll be disintegrated
like that.
- [Tom] Nucular?
Nucular.
- Sabotage.
- [All] Gesundheit.
- Somebody switched
all our wiring.
Dropo's gone, your
suit is missing.
- Gates has been confirmed.
- And now this machine's
been sabotaged.
Put them all together,
it spells Voldar.
- He was here.
- [Tom] Or "mother".
- And he thought Dropo was me.
- He's got Dropo, and
I'm gonna find him.
- Poor Dropo.
♪ Poor Dropo's dead, poor ♪
- Surprised to see us?
- You're under arrest, Voldar.
(laughing)
- [Joel] He's a great
audience, what can ya say?
- Stop playing with toys.
Put it away, Kimar.
- [Tom] It's an Air Blaster.
- We have a weapon that's
much more potent than that.
As you may know, we are
holding Santa Claus a hostage.
One false move, and your little
ho ho ho-man will be destroyed.
- [Tom] Who's he calling a ho?
- All right, what
do you want, Voldar?
- These are our terms.
- Big mosquito, sorry.
- First, destroy
the toy machine.
Second, we will
release Santa Claus
if you promise to send
him and the Earthlings
back to their planet.
Third, no more joy through
toys nonsense on Mars.
- [Tom] And D, we want all
political prisoners released.
- Well, you win.
Are you sure you
have Santa Claus?
- [Voldar] You know we have him.
- You mean you had him.
- [Joel] You know,
if Charlie Callas
and Jamie Farr had a son.
- How did he get
out of the cage?
- Shim, that idiot!
- And, and how'd he
get here s-so fast?
- Santa Claus has powers
that you don't know about.
All right, arms up.
Rigna, Hargo, Lomas, report!
- [Rigna] This is Rigna, Kimar.
Hargo and Lomas are with me.
- What about Poopoo and Caca?
- I've got Voldar and Stobo.
- [Tom] What about
Ringjob and Sluggy?
- I'll keep them here in the
storeroom of the toy shop.
Rigna, you come here and
take them off my hands.
I want Hargo and Lomas to
look for a man named Shim.
Tell him to search the caves
along the Transverse Canal.
- [Rigna] Right, Kimar.
- All right, you two, in there.
- [Joel] Why is he tap-dancing?
Is he Gregory Hines?
- He's a trooper.
- All right, you
might as well relax.
You're gonna be here
for a while, sit down.
- Oh man, the janitor's closet.
Smells like someone's
been tanning leather.
- [Tom] Ooh.
♪ I want my MTV ♪
- [Joel] Huh?
We've secretly replaced
the light bulbs
with Folger's crystals.
Let's see what happens.
- [Tom] Here at GE, we
bring Dropo to light.
- How many Dropos does it
take to change a light bulb?
- [Shim] Where are you going?
- Ho ho ho!
- Can't you say anything
else but ho ho ho?
- [Tom] No no no!
- If you're thinking
of leaving, Santa,
let me remind you.
- Leaving Santa?
- Once you hit that
nucular curtain,
- Nuclear, nuclear!
- There won't be a whisker left.
- Ho ho ho!
- Hey, Santa, be careful!
(Crow groaning)
- Jumping Jehosaphat!
- [Joel] Hmm.
(mellow music)
- What are you gonna do with us?
- [Crow] We're
going water skiing.
- You're gonna stand
trial before the Council.
I don't think you'll be
causing any more trouble.
- [Joel] Ah, the old
manic ski disarm.
(dramatic music)
- [Tom] What was a water
ski doing there, anyway?
Let's see here, is it?
- Well now, I think
that should do it.
- [Tom] Cheap Martian crap.
- Close the door, son.
Now, I think we need
a little red paint,
and you'll find it
in the storeroom.
- Next to the fairy dust.
- Sure, Santa.
- Uh, but don't look
in the duffel bag.
- [Joel] The store
room, wait a minute!
He's on a collision
course with wackiness!
- [Voldar] Santa Claus for
good, and smash that machine!
- Santa, Santa!
Voldar and another man
are in the storeroom
and they're coming to get you!
- With Ringjob and Foofoo!
- They are, are they?
Well, maybe they'd like to
have some fun with our toys,
and we'll see that they do.
Won't we, kids?
Psst!
(lively music)
(whispering)
- [Joel] Blow dry
and a rinse, old man?
- Oho, we meet again, eh?
- I don't know how
you escaped Shim,
but you won't escape me.
You're through!
- Voldar, why don't
you, uh, relax?
- You're going to
relax permanently.
- [Tom] Ooh!
Good idea, risk the
kids' lives, Santa.
(playful music)
Oh, hilarity, guys.
Not since the pie fight
scene in "The Great Race."
- Not since the mud slide
scene is "McClintock."
- [Joel] Not since
the wagon race scene
in "The Hallelujah Trail."
- Not since the chess-playing
scene in "The Seventh Seal."
- [Tom] Not since the
orgy scene in "Caligula."
- What?
- Huh?
- [Tom] Hilarity, anyway.
- Santa's doing his Ali!
Float like a butterfly.
- [Joel] I protest.
- [Tom] I don't blame you.
- Oh, this is great.
Okay, teach your kids to
throw dangerous toys around.
- [Joel] Again, I protest.
- [Tom] Kids, this is hell.
- Sorta like the Twilight Zone.
- [Joel] It's day
care in Beirut.
- Haha, good blocking, this
scene was well thought out.
(laughing)
- [Joel] It's kinda like the
final scene in "Killdozer!".
- [Tom] Huh?
- You!
But, but you're not here!
You're in there!
- Oh, yeah, you're
right, I'm not here.
I'm in there!
- [Tom] Yeah, and you're
your own grandpa, too.
- [Joel] You know,
I can't see what kid
could figure this movie
out, I'm confused.
- [All] Womp-womp-womp!
- I dunno what's
going on in there,
but I'm gonna take
care of you myself!
- Now, now just a minute!
I'd like to talk to--
- [Tom] Gimme that Air Blaster.
- Oh boy, Chief, am
I glad to see you.
- All right, inside, Stobo.
- [Joel] Altogether now,
with a one and a two.
- All right, kids,
you can stop now.
I said cease fire!
- [Tom] You know, drug abuse
is a horrible thing, isn't it?
- All right, Rigna,
take them away.
They've had a rough day.
- [Joel] Oh, he's
being wry and ironic.
- [Tom] Don't forget to read 'em
their Carmen Miranda rights.
- Ho ho ho, everybody!
Merry Christmas!
(laughing)
- Oh, shut up.
- Please.
- You don't need me here, Kimar.
You've got a wonderful
Santa Claus of your own.
(laughing)
- Ho ho ho!
- Aw, shut up, it's
just not that funny!
- Goodbye, Billy.
- Headbutt.
- Goodbye, Betty dear.
- You take care of yourself.
- [Tom] Hope you find your
natural parents, kids.
- Bye.
- I've got something
for you, Billy.
- Gee, thanks!
- [Joel] And it's ticking!
- Goodbye.
- Bye.
Gee, we had fun.
- We're going to miss you.
- [Tom] Here's my Golden
Globe award that my--
- I'm sure you will, children.
Thank you, Santa, for
bringing happiness
to the children of Mars.
- Again.
- And the Christmas
spirit to all of us.
- Son, from the
bottom of my heart.
- [Tom] I say bite me.
Oh, I'm kidding, of
course, ho ho ho!
- I wish you and yours the
very best of everything.
- Oh no, no.
- Ho ho ho!
Merry Christmas!
- You never learn.
- Dropo, you've put on weight.
(laughing)
- Hey, it's the
Round John Virgin!
- Look, look, kids, no pillows!
(booming)
- Oops, there goes his appendix.
- His water broke.
- Isn't that how Houdini died?
- Yeah.
- Yep.
- Now, if we hurry,
we can get back
in time for Christmas Eve.
- Yay!
- Shall we get going?
- Shall we stuff that
goofy guy in a duffel bag?
- [All] Yay!
- Goodbye, dear friends.
- [Tom] What is this,
"The Long Goodbye?"
Just leave, get outta here!
Geez.
- Merry Christmas!
- Arsenio Hall!
- [Joel] Woo, woo, woo, woo!
- [Kimar] Bye, Santa Claus!
- Hey, take some
pancakes with you!
♪ They'll die in the vacuum ♪
♪ They'll burn on re-entry ♪
- [Joel] Tom, you can't do that.
- [Tom] I'm sorry, it is
Santa Claus, isn't it?
I'm sorry.
(Tom humming)
♪ Hang out in leather bars ♪
♪ Pile on the cocktail sauce ♪
- [Joel] Will you stop it?
- I'm just--
- Come on.
- Santa Claus,
killed in Vietnam.
- [Joel] Filmed in
Christmas Cardvision.
- [Tom] You guys
are doing it too.
- [Joel] No we're
not, what we're doing
is totally different
than what you're doing.
- Hey, look, it's Jackie
Gleason, and he's mooning us!
- [Joel] See, that
is totally different,
it's totally different.
- [Tom] Okay, let me try
one here, let me wind up.
You know, you can almost see
the ozone layer disappearing.
- [Joel] Oh, he just
doesn't get it, does he?
- No.
- Would you stop that?
- [Tom] What, what, what?
- [Joel] I implore
you, I do not see
what you are going on about.
♪ Hooray for Gummi
Bears, doo doo doo ♪
- Merry Christmas, guys.
- [Tom] Merry Christmas, Crow.
Merry Christmas, Joel.
Can we get outta
here now, please?
- We'll miss this!
- [Tom] That's okay.
- [Joel] Like anybody
cares who Hargo is.
♪ Hooray for James Cahill ♪
- Oh good, Shim was Joe Elic.
- [Joel] Lomas was Jim Bishop.
♪ Santa's helpers stunk,
doo doo doo doo doo ♪
♪ Haul out the rum and gin ♪
- [Tom] Oh, they
got words for us.
- Ho ho ho
♪ On Christmas day
you'll wake up and say ♪
♪ Hooray for Santy Claus ♪
♪ S-A-T-A-N, N-T-A ♪
♪ Hooray for Sanity Claus ♪
Is it over now?
Oh, geez.
♪ S-A-N-T-A C-L-A-U-S ♪
- [Joel] You spell
it Santa Claus,
but you say it Santy Claus.
- Enough already!
- This whole Christmas
has been one ugly.
♪ Hooray for Santy Claus ♪
♪ Angels we have
heard are high ♪
♪ Softly sipping old champagne ♪
♪ Oh oh oh oh oh oh ♪
♪ Oh oh oh Oreos ♪
♪ Inexpensive danish ♪
- All right!
- Stocking time, stocking time!
- Yeah, stocking time!
Okay, hold it, hold it.
We're gonna do our stockings,
and then it's time
for bed, okay?
- Okay, okay.
- Who's first?
- All right, here we go.
- Sock it to me.
- All right, this
first one's for Gypsy.
- Yay!
- And look at what
we got in there.
- Oh, Richard Glazier!
Joel, how did you know?
- Oh, I dunno, I
just knew, okay?
- How did he know?
- My turn, my turn!
- Thank you, Gypsy.
And here's Tom's, let's
empty that out here.
- Say, apple, look
at all the loot!
- He got a lot of
stuff in his stocking.
- Yeah, he did, isn't
that great, Crow?
- Really cool.
- Yeah, really great.
- Okay, and here's.
- Thank you Santa,
thank you Santa!
- Here's Crow's.
- Oh, wow, I.
- What'd you get,
Crow, what'd you get?
- Um, well, uh, my stocking's
got a breathable cotton panel.
- Say!
- Oh, well, and then
this, oh, you guys!
- That's for you!
Open it, Joel, open it!
- Where did you find this?
- Oh, Gypsy found it
in the laundry chute.
- Oh, okay.
Okay, okay.
- Read it, read it!
I mean open it.
- You blew it, Gypsy.
- Oh, we got a letter
here, everybody.
Okay, let's put that up on
still store, Cambot, good.
Okay, "Dear Crow, Tom
Servo, and Gypsy."
- [Bots] Yay!
- "Greetings and pleasantries
from the great NW.
"As the Christmas season begins,
"familiar thoughts
and feelings abound.
"The slight chill in the air,
which you can almost see,
"reflecting on years past.
"Family togetherness
gains more import
"on one's list of priorities,
and society begins
"to once again plug into
retail commercialism
"and capitalism in search of
the perfect yuletide gifts.
"Your creation is the
only TV program I watch,
"or used to watch.
"My husband here and
I are experiencing
"a physical separation now,
as I'm in the Coast Guard
"stationed in Seattle.
"MST3K brings us
closer somehow in this.
"Is this too schlocky?
"I can spout out sophomoric
drivel like nobody's beeswax.
"My apologies.
"Thank you.
"Thank you, MST3K, for making
us laugh at love, again.
"Graciously yours,
Jennifer Jacobs."
Merry Christmas, everybody!
- Merry Christmas, Joel!
- Merry Christmas, sirs!
- Frank, I, I can't wait.
I want you to open
your gift now.
- Great idea, P.
As a matter of fact,
uh, I've picked you up
a little something myself.
- For me?
Oh, you, you shouldn't have.
- It was nothing, really.
- Oh, Frank, no, it's
the thought that counts.
I, I know that you
think that I'm probably
just a cold-hearted
jerk without an ounce
of self respect for
myself or anyone else,
but on the other hand.
- Merry Christmas,
Dr. Forrester.
- Merry Christmas, Frank.
Oh, Frank, what a
lovely watch band!
This must have set you
back a pretty penny.
- Well, actually, I, uh,
didn't have any money,
so I took the liberty
of hocking your Rolex,
to pay for that.
- You hocked my Rolex.
- Yeah.
- Well, it's the
thought that counts.
Open your gift.
- Oh boy, I bet it's a
book, I bet it's a book!
- Yes, it is a book, Frank.
It's called "Final Exit."
I've been stealing
your plasma at night
so I didn't have to spend
any of my own money.
- Oh, Henry.
- Well, until next time, Bumpus.
- God bless us, every one.
Ow.
Ah.
(mellow music)
(laughing)